Good morning everyone
Today I will discuss the Discrete Fourier Transform
You know in the time domain and the frequency domain
we learn a lot of different type of following transforms
First of all is Continue aperiodical signal
in the time domain
and the following transform
in the frequency domain is also Continue aperiodical
Ok that is the continue signals Fourier Transform
in the time domain and the frequency domain
This is the first Fourier Transform
we learn in the signals and systems before this course
And if the signal in the time domain is periodical
the signal in the time domain is periodical
what happen will in the frequency domain
It will be discrete spectrum
Think it about
Why
Why periodical signal in the time domain
the Fourier Transform is discrete spectrum
We call it line-spectrum
Why
Just a moment
If the signal in the time domain is discrete
what happen will in the frequency domain
It¡¯s periodical spectrum
You can see this two
if in the time domain the signal is periodical
the spectrum will be discrete
And if in the time domain the signal is discrete
the spectrum will be periodical
And if the signal in the time domain
is discrete and periodical
discrete and periodical
what happen will in the frequency domain
The spectrum will be periodical and discrete
You can see both in time domain
and in frequency domain the signal
is discrete and periodical
So you can see
we have four different types of Fourier Transform
Why we need the last one-DFT
The DTFT is Discrete Time Fourier Transform
And DFT is Discrete Fourier Transform
What¡¯s the difference between the last two
The DTFT Discrete Time Fourier Transform
And DFT Discrete Fourier Transform
What¡¯s the difference
Typical DFT Pair ¦ÄT(t) is a ¦Ä train
a lot of equal distance
discrete in both
The period is capital T
And the spectrum is ¦Ä¦Ø0
You can see both side
in the time domain ¦ÄT(t)
and in the frequency domain ¦Ä¦Ø0
we see
with the DFT  is
both side discrete and periodical
and the period is capital T
And in the frequency domain
what about the period
¦Ø0
And what¡¯s the relationship between capital T and ¦Øo
Yeah that¡¯s good
You can see
¦Ø0 = 2¦Ğ/T
here
of course
this is discrete and periodical
the period is capital T
And here
the frequency domain of course is
discrete and periodical
the period is ¦Ø0
So this is a typical DFT pair
In DFT the signals in both sides are discrete
so it is the only transform pair
which can be processed by computer
Why we need DFT
Just because we want to use
computer to process the signals
And you know
within a digital computer
there are only zero and one in the computer
nothing else
Of course
a lot of tremendous number of zero and one in a computer
So all of the signals if you want to process
it must be discrete
That¡¯s right
And both sides must be discrete
So that¡¯s why we need DFT
Just because
both sides
in the time domain and the frequency domain
are discrete
So we can use computer to process it
The signals in both sides are periodical
so the processing could be in one period
Why
Just because it¡¯s periodical
What does it mean periodical
That mean in each period
all of the signal is exactly the same
That's Right
Just repeat and repeat and repeat and repeat
So we can only process one period
It¡¯s enough because all period is the same
So that means the number of calculation is limited
Just one period
so the calculation number is limited
And which is necessary for computer
Of course  it¡¯s necessary for computer
Computer maybe very very fast
means can process a lot of signals in one period
Ok
But the number must be limited
But for the period signal
in one period
the number is limited
so that is necessary to
use a computer to process the signals
And all of the signal information
could be kept in one period
All of the information
keep in one period
That¡¯s right
Of course yes
Why
Just because it¡¯s period
Each all of period is exactly the same
So one period keeps all of the signal information
Ok
So so which is necessary for accurate processing
You can accurate process because
if you want to process another period
you can not get anymore information
Because Each all of period
is exactly the same information
So this is why we need DFT
and DFT is the only Fourier Transform
can use computer to process
The example is the natural signal
Almost all of the natural signals are continue
That¡¯s right
Natural signal
almost all of the signals are continue
analog signals
But now
just because we want to process signal with computer
we have to change the continue signal into the discrete
Ok
So the title is to make a signal discrete and periodical
Pay attention here
make  we have to make the continue signal
into discrete and periodical
We have to do it
because the computer can
process only discrete
just both sides are discrete
so both sides are periodical
First of all
we would like to have both sides are discrete
and then
just because both sides are discrete
so both sides must be periodical
And the period is just the same
In the natural signals
almost all of the natural signals are continue
so we need to make the signal discrete first
And then we can use computer to process it
The problem is how
How make the natural signals into discrete
The engineering signals are often continue
I say almost all of the signals in engineering
that means the natural signals are continue and periodical
So if we want to process the signals with DFT
Discrete Fourier Transform
both sides are discrete and periodical
We have to make the signals discrete and periodical
make the natural continuous and
periodical signal into a discrete and periodical signal
How
Sampling to make the signal discrete
And make the signal periodical
How
How make the signal periodical
If x[n] is a limited length
limited length that means only limited number in samples
that means a limited length N-point sequence
see it as one period of a periodical signal
see the limited length signal as one period
and see it as just one period of a periodical signal
that means extend it to a periodical
One is limited number
we see the limited number signal as one period
and extend it to periodical
Ok
It¡¯s easy
very easy
So first of all
if this is a limited number signal
extend it to periodical
Just see the limited number signal
as one period of a periodical signal
But if x[n] is not limited
if x[n] is an infinite length sequence
cut off the tails
make it limited
ok
It¡¯s easy
cut off the tails
both sides
make it limited and then what
Cut off the tails first
and then
see this limited number signal
as one period of a periodical sequence
That¡¯s right
Go back to limited number
so in this way we make
an aperiodical signal into a periodical
Of course you can say no
cut off the tails will introduce what
Error
Of course introduce error
In the engineering
we always make such mistakes
You here
everybody will be an engineer
You know we always make such mistakes
Introduce error
we have to
Why
Because we want to use computer to process it
Because we are lazy
that¡¯s right
You know the people how to make innovation
just because people are lazy
They invent all of the new things
just because we are lazy
So just because we want to process signals with computer
so we have to make the signal discrete and periodical
But original signal is continue and aperiodical
but we make it discrete and periodical
Of course we will introduce error
But we have to do it
We have to stay with it
Ok
So here
you can see
we must develop truncation algorithm to reduce the error
which is windowing
So you know
if you make the continue signal into discrete
of course
we introduce error
And you want to make an aperiodical signal into a periodical
we introduce a cut-off tails
So of course
we introduce error
The problem is how to reduce it
How to reduce error
No error is impossible
Of course  No error is impossible
The problem is how to make how to reduce the error
So we have windowing
You will learn more about the windowing later
Ok
thank you